Nibil M S

Email: me@nibil.in / snibil@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9495 41 2790

skype : sayyidnibil

Summary

I'm a Techno-Functional professional who started my career as the first employee of a startup. I started off as a Development Engineer, later on transitioning myself to a managerial role in the second-tier leadership of the company while continuing my role as a Product Engineer in the company. In my 5-year stint with the startup, the company grew from 5 to 72 people. I have had the opportunity to experience the initial hiccups, the effective bootstrapping, external investment, acquisition and the growth of the company from multiple roles and perspectives.

I then associated with some companies as a consultant in both service and product background and has worked with clients across the world. I am now looking for exciting challenges where I can put my tech + management skills.

Work Experience

Consultant (November 2019 to Present)

SalutaryData, Boston, United States (www.salutarydata.com)

- Working directly under CTO
- Maintain the database up to date by adding the vendor data
- Normalise various vendor data
- Update the data stats for CEO
- Pull out the required data as per client requests for the sales team
- Writing MySQL queries
- Bash and Python language scripting

VP of Operations (Feb 2018 to Present)

Leadlytics Data Labs, Kerala, India (www.leadlyticslabs.com)

- Interact with clients to understand their needs
- Define the process for every client to make sure their expectations are met
- Help the HR team in the recruitment and onboarding process.
- Lead the D2D operations
- Defined the architecture and lead the development of the internal Django web app
- Python language scripting.

Consultant (December 2016 to May 2018)

PropsAMC, Karnataka, India (<u>www.propsamc.com</u>) (January 2018 - May 2018)

- Lead the product team and report to the CTO.
- Do the research and check the feasibility of the features.
- Define the features and software architecture of the product's version 2.0
- Lead the development and do the backend revamp using Django and VueJS
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

Vogo Automotive, Karnataka, India (<u>www.vogo.in</u>) (April 2017 - November 2017)

- Lead the product team and report to the CTO.
- Do the research and check the feasibility of the features.
- Define the features and software architecture of the product's version 2.0
- Lead the development and do the backend revamp using the Django Rest Framework.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

RawData Technologies, Kerala, India (<u>www.rawdatatech.com</u>) (November 2016 - March 2017)

- Reporting directly to the CEO, responsible for the handling service project WinWinUSA
- Interact with client to understand requirements, check feasibility & provide best suitable estimation accordingly.
- Deeply involved in recruiting developers into the team.
- Do code reviews and appraisals of developers

VP of Data Research (July 2014 to August 2016)

Profoundis Labs, Kerala

- Profoundis developed their flagship product (https://vibeapp.co) backed by a Human + Technology Hybrid engine which has been acquired by FullContact (https://fullcontact.com).
- As there was a need to grow Data Research as a function in the company, I gradually transitioned into a business role with client interactions.
- Directly reporting to Co-founder & Chief of Data Research, I led the operations side of data research function with the whole Data Research Team functionally reporting to me.
- Was also involved deeply in the recruitment, onboarding, training, performance appraisals as the team grew from 10 to 72.
- Part of the team that developed and maintained the internal Django web app that augmented the Data Research process.
- Python language scripting.

Senior Product Engineer (July 2012 to June 2014)

Profoundis Labs Private Ltd, Kerala (www.profoundis.com)

- Joined Profoundis as the first employee after the first month of the company's inception.
- Reporting directly to the CTO of the company; responsible for the services side of Profoundis which was then bootstrapping.
- Worked with clients from Turkey, the Middle East and the US including the likes of Vodafone which cumulatively earned over 100,000\$ for the company.
- Mostly worked with Python, Django, HTML and Javascript during this tenure.

Django Developer (August 2011 to June 2012)

As a prodigy of Mr Kenneth Gonsalves (Chairman, Indian Python Software Society, 2010 2011)

- Worked on multiple projects including the development and maintenance of Websites and Web applications in Python/Django.
- Clients included FIDA Kids (an NGO based out of Africa and India), Bamboo Banks (Ooty based hotel) and Ooty Golf Course.

Education

 Master of Business Administration in Project Management Bharathiar University, Coimbatore (Pursuing)

• Master of Science in Computer Science

Kalinga University, Raipur

• Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

Mewar University, Chittorgarh

• Bachelor of Computer Application

Madurai Kamaraj University, Madurai

• Higher Secondary Examination

Govt Higher Secondary School, Kumaranellur

• Technical High School Leaving Certificate

Technical Higher Secondary School, Vattamkulam

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages and Frameworks:
 - Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, Pandas, Javascript (basics)
- Databases
 - PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Elasticsearch, MongoDB

Management Skills

- Business sense with a technology background.
- Leadership, Interpersonal and team skills
- Initiating, leading and optimizing day to day operations of a team at scale.
- Recruiting and building a team

Personal Information

Name : Nibil M S Sex : Male

Address : Needam, Trithala P.O, Palakkad-679534, Kerala, IN

Date of Birth : 06-10-1989 Marital Status : Married

Passport : Indian (#K3080682) Languages Known : English, Malayalam, Tamil

References

- 1. <u>Jeff Clewley</u>, CTO of Salutary Data
- 2. Arjun R Pillai, CEO of Insent.ai
- 3. Anoop Thomas Mathew, Head of Technology, Data Strategy at FullContact Inc
- 4. Nithin Sam Oommen, CEO of Leadlytics Data Labs
- 5. <u>Jofin Joseph</u>, GM at FullContact India